Guide to the Cedric J. Robinson and Elizabeth P. Robinson Collection on Third World News Review TAM.835
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series II: Third World News Review Episodes, 1981-2015; 1.67 Linear Feet in 2 manuscript boxes and a cassette box; 1.79 Terabytes in 496 computer files; 3 U-matic; 15 VHS; 29 audiocassettes
  - May 22, 2006, TW_TAM_835_ER_123
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Katia McClain and Elizabeth Robinson. Discussed topics include the Iraq War, a referendum on whether Montenegro should leave the union with Serbia, and the discovery of a Rwandan genocide suspect living freely in London.
  - June 5, 2006, TW_TAM_835_ER_124
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Elizabeth Robinson and Gerard Pigeon. Discussed topics include Pfizer's controversial clinical trials in Nigeria; the Iraq War; the ongoing conflict between Israel and Palestine; Latin American medical fields; and increased African immigration to Europe.
  - June 12, 2006, TW_TAM_835_ER_125
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Gary Colmenar and Elizabeth Robinson. Discussed topics include Guantanamo prison; the Iraq War; the ongoing conflicts between Israel and Palestine; Filipino Independence Day; and Filipino politics.
  - June 19, 2006, TW_TAM_835_ER_126
    The moderator of the episode was Elizabeth Robinson and the guests were Hector Javkin and Katia McClain. Discussed topics include the gay rights movement in Russia; homophobia in Eastern Europe; Julius and Ethel Rosenberg; the School of the Americas Watch Organization; and the Iraq War.
  - June 26, 2006, TW_TAM_835_ER_127
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Gerard Pigeon and Elizabeth Robinson. Discussed topics include the Iraq War; U.S. support of warlords in Somalia; the World Cup and its ties to colonialism; and Homeland Security making arrests under the suspicion of terrorism.
  - July 10, 2006, TW_TAM_835_ER_128
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Elizabeth Robinson and Hector Javkin. Discussed topics include the Iraq War; the ongoing conflicts between Israel and Palestine; torture carried out by past Argentinian military governments; and Mexican politics.
  - July 17, 2006, TW_TAM_835_ER_129
    The moderator of the episode was Elizabeth Robinson and the guests were Katia McClain and Gerard Pigeon. Discussed topics include the growing tensions between Israel and Hezbollah; tensions at the G8 Summit; and the World Cup and its ties to racism.
  - July 24, 2006, TW_TAM_835_ER_130
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Hector Javkin and Elizabeth Robinson. Discussed topics include the ongoing conflicts between Israel and Palestine; corruption in the Mexican election; Haitian debt; and a call for the cancellation of debt internationally.
  - July 31, 2006
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Thomas Jacob and Gerard Pigeon. Discussed topics include a train blast in India and its impact on peace talks with Pakistan; the Doha Round; the civil war in Nepal; deaths of Lebanese civilians; the ongoing conflicts between Israel and Palestine; and Condoleeza Rice's visit to the Middle East and Malaysia.
    - Audio (Box 4, Audiocassette 835_0013)
    - Digital Video Recording, TW_TAM_835_ER_131
  - August 7, 2006, TW_TAM_835_ER_132
    The moderator of the episode was Elizabeth Robinson and the guests were HH.L.T (HQ) Quan (Asia), Gerard Pigeon, and Cedric Robinson. Discussed topics include political and economic instability in the Democratic Republic of the Congo; China's economic relationship with Africa; a ceasefire agreement by the U.S. and France rejected by Lebanon; and tensions between Israel and Lebanon.
  - August 14, 2006, TW_TAM_835_ER_133
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Hector Javkin and Elizabeth Robinson. Discussed topics include conflict between Israel and Lebanon, and President Fidel Castro and how he is perceived in the U.S. versus Latin America.
  - August 21, 2006
    The moderator of the episode was Katia McClain and the guests were Corey Dubin and Phoebe Hirsch-Dubin (Mexico). Discussed topics include the gubernatorial election in Chiapas; politics in Chiapas and Oaxaca; the 16th World AIDS Conference; and pharmaceutical industries and medical resources globally.
    - Audio (Box 4, Audiocassette 835_0010)
    - Digital Video Recording, TW_TAM_835_ER_134
  - August 28, 2006, TW_TAM_835_ER_135
    The moderator of the episode was Hector Javkin and the guests were Gerard Pigeon and Thomas Jacob. Discussed topics include the assassination of Nawab Akhbar Khan; the Tamil Tigers; a film about the occupation of Iraq; the conflict between Israel and Hezbollah; the Congolese elections; and President Fidel Castro's surgery.
  - September 11, 2006, TW_TAM_835_ER_136
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Gerard Pigeon and Hector Javkin. Discussed topics include the 9/11 attacks and the Iraq War; death and sickness after toxic waste was dumped in Abidjan, Ivory Coast; a coup on Salvador Allende; U.S. interference in Chile; and opposition to Nestor Kirchner in Argentina.
  - September 18, 2006
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Thomas Jacob and Elizabeth Robinson. Discussed topics include Iran's nuclear weapons program in Iran, the Israel-Lebanon conflict, Operation Medusa, the war in Afghanistan and the Congolese presidential elections.
    - Audio (Box 4, Audiocassette 835_0014)
    - Digital Video Recording, TW_TAM_835_ER_137
  - September 25, 2006, TW_TAM_835_ER_138
    The moderator of the episode was Elizabeth Robinson and the guests were Hector Javkin and Cedric Robinson. Discussed topics include the Iraq War and growing terrorism; negotiations between the Ugandan government and the Lord's Resistance Army leader, Joseph Kony; the Union of Islamic Court's control over Somalia; the murder of the Director of the Ministry of Women's Affairs in Afghanistan; the 14th Non Aligned Movement Summit; and President Hugo Chávez's portrayal in American media.
  - October 9, 2006
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Gerard Pigeon and Katia McClain. Discussed topics include the murder of Anna Politkovskaya and political corruption in Russia; protests in Hungary against Prime Minister Ferenc Gyurcsány; political instability in Somalia; a breakdown of negotiations between the Lord's Resistance Army and Ugandan government; and a political conflict in France due to an increased number of African immigrants.
    - Audio (Box 4, Audiocassette 835_0027)
    - Digital Video Recording, TW_TAM_835_ER_139
  - October 16, 2006
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Elizabeth Robinson and Hector Javkin. Discussed topics include the Truth and Reconciliation Commission of Liberia; ongoing conflict between Israel and Palestine; and the disappearance of Jorge Julio Lopez in Argentina after testifying against Miguel Etchecolatz.
    - Audio (Box 4, Audiocassette 835_0007)
    - Digital Video Recording, TW_TAM_835_ER_140
  - October 23, 2006, TW_TAM_835_ER_141
    The moderator of the episode was Elizabeth Robinson and the guests were Gary Colmenar and Katia McClain. Discussed topics include non-governmental organizations in Russia, foreign medical workers on trial in Libya, Orhan Pamuk wins the Nobel Prize for literature, Mohammad Yunus's microbanking schemes, and Condoleeza Rice's tour of Asia.
  - October 30, 2006
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Brian Brown (Mexico) and Elizabeth Robinson. Discussed topics include political unrest in Oaxaca, the Congolese presidential election, global child labor, and the use of phosphorus weapons by Israel in Lebanon.
    - Audio (Box 4, Audiocassette 835_0004)
    - Digital Video Recording, TW_TAM_835_ER_142
  - November 6, 2006
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Hector Javkin and Gerard Pigeon. Discussed topics include a strict ban of abortion in Nicaragua, Nicaraguan politics, and Daniel Ortega; the Dengue fever epidemic in Cuba; and the economic relationship between China and Africa.
    - Audio (Box 4, Audiocassette 835_0010)
    - Digital Video Recording, TW_TAM_835_ER_143
  - November 20, 2006
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Gerard Pigeon and Hector Javkin. Discussed topics include elections in the Democratic Republic of the Congo and growing military conflicts there; the economies of various African nations; ongoing military conflicts in Uganda; and demonstrations at the School of the Americas.
    - Audio (Box 4, Audiocassette 835_0013)
    - Digital Video Recording, TW_TAM_835_ER_144
  - November 27, 2006, TW_TAM_835_ER_145
    The moderator of the episode was Elizabeth Robinson and the guests were Gary Colmenar and Hector Javkin. Discussed topics include political conflicts between Venezuela and Argentina over the international arrest warrants for eight Iranian former cabinet ministers; the Ecuadorian elections; influence of the U.S. on the Philippines; scandal surrounding President Gloria Macapagal Arroyo; and the Iraq War.
  - December 4, 2006, TW_TAM_835_ER_146
    The moderator of the episode was Elizabeth Robinson and the guests were Gerard Pigeon and Katia McClain. Discussed topics include the death of Alexander Litvinenko; tension between Presidents Vladimir Putin and George W. Bush; France's historic and current involvement in Africa; growing racial tensions in France; and elections in Haiti.
  - December 11, 2006, TW_TAM_835_ER_147
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Jennifer Rogers (Mexico) and Elizabeth Robinson. Discussed topics include the dissertation of sociology graduate student Jennifer Rogers on the 2006 Oaxaca movement, ongoing pro-Hezbollah demonstrations in Lebanon, the Arab League, and speculations about Israel's nuclear weapons program.
  - December 18, 2006, TW_TAM_835_ER_148
    The moderator of the episode was Elizabeth Robinson and the guests were Gerard Pigeon and Hector Javkin. Discussed topics include the history of General Augusto Pinochet; increased migration out of South Africa to Europe, the Middle East, or northern parts of Africa; and the immigration policies of various European nations like Spain, Italy, and Germany.
  - January 8, 2007, TW_TAM_835_ER_149
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Hector Javkin, Gerard Pigeon, and Elizabeth Robinson. Discussed topics include the film Iraq in Fragment; banking and record-setting tax revenues in Argentina; and the impact of films on political decisions in France.
  - January 22, 2007, TW_TAM_835_ER_150
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Katia McClain and Gerard Pigeon. Discussed topics include Bulgaria and Romania joining the European Union; discrimination against Roma communities throughout Europe; the Serbian elections and politics; and the politics, economy, corruption, trade union strikes, and demonstrations in Guinea.
  - January 29, 2007, TW_TAM_835_ER_151
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Hector Javkin and Gerard Pigeon. Discussed topics include the death of Ugandan rebel Alice Auma Lakwena; U.S. support for resistance against the Union of Islamic Courts in Somalia; an African Union meeting in Libya; opposition to the governor of Cochabamba, Bolivia; demonstrations against the Iraq War throughout the U.S.; and land rights for Bushmen in South Africa.
  - February 5, 2007, TW_TAM_835_ER_152
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Katia McClain and Elizabeth Robinson. Discussed topics include the 7th World Social Forum held in Kenya; the economy and debt cancellation in Africa; the Palestinian presence at the forum; the ethnic and religious composition of Kosovo; and economic pressures on Yugoslavia.
  - February 12, 2007, TW_TAM_835_ER_153
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Hector Javkin and Elizabeth Robinson. Discussed topics include the Iraq War; Iran's nuclear weapons capabilities; Carnaval in Cochabamba, Bolivia; the U.S. not participating with a treaty that bans secret detentions; U.S.-Brazilian negotiations on ethanol and energy concerns; and the death of South African activist Adelaide Tambo.
  - February 26, 2007, TW_TAM_835_ER_154
    The moderator of the episode was Elizabeth Robinson and the guests were Gary Colmenar and Katia McClain. Discussed topics include a complaint by Bosnia and Herzegovina against Serbia and Montenegro at the International Court of Justice for acts of genocide; violence in the former Yugoslavia; President Vladimir Putin's criticism of U.S. military force abroad; the 21st anniversary of the People Power Revolution in the Philippines; and political killings in the Philippines.
  - March 5, 2007, TW_TAM_835_ER_155
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Hector Javkin and Elizabeth Robinson. Discussed topics include the 50th anniversary celebration of Ghanaian independence; severe flooding in Trinidad and Bolivia; the murder of Salvadoran Arena party members; President George W. Bush's trip to Brazil, Uruguay, and Argentina; the killing of civilians in Afghanistan by NATO actions and the U.S. military; and the ongoing conflict between Israel and Palestine.
  - March 19, 2007, TW_TAM_835_ER_156
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Hector Javkin and Elizabeth Robinson. Discussed topics include a comparison between the Latin American tours of President George W. Bush and President Hugo Chávez; the death of Tanya Reinhart; the ongoing conflict between Israel and Palestine; the ongoing conflict between Israel and Lebanon; and the Iraq War.
  - March 26, 2007, TW_TAM_835_ER_157
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Gary Colmenar and Gerard Pigeon. Discussed topics include post-election news in the Democratic Republic of the Congo; the indictments of President Joseph Kabila and Jean-Pierre Bemba of war crimes; investigation of Nigerian president Olusegun Obasanjo; Islamic Court rebellion in East Africa; protests in Philippines against Gloria Macapagal Arroyo; and the French elections.
  - April 2, 2007, TW_TAM_835_ER_158
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Katia McClain and Gerard Pigeon. Discussed topics include a mine explosion in the Kemerovo region of Russia; the suppression of anti-fascist demonstrations in Russia and the upcoming Russian elections; the U.S. announcing a potential strike against Iran; questions surrounding the future of Kosovo; biofuel; and the election of Guillaume Soro as prime minister of Ivory Coast.
  - April 9, 2007, TW_TAM_835_ER_159
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Hector Javkin and Elizabeth Robinson. Discussed topics include the four year anniversary of the fall of Baghdad and the pulling down of Saddam Hussein's statue; the Iraq War; questions about Iran's nuclear program; protests in Argentina and the upcoming teacher strikes; a meeting between President George W. Bush and President Lula da Silva of Brazil; and politics in Zimbabwe.
  - April 30, 2007, TW_TAM_835_ER_160
    The moderator of the episode was Elizabeth Robinson and the guests were Cedric Robinson and Gerard Pigeon. Discussed topics include the Nigerian and French elections; the war between the Somali military and Ethiopian troops versus insurgents; growing rates of immigration and xenophobia in France; and the Israeli invasion of Lebanon.
  - May 14, 2007, TW_TAM_835_ER_161
    The moderator of the episode was Elizabeth Robinson and the guests were Gerard Pigeon and Hector Javkin. Discussed topics include denial of women's rights in Afghanistan; the impact of globalization on Africa; the French elections; economic migration to the U.S.; and the teacher strikes and heavy police repression in Argentina.
  - May 21, 2007, TW_TAM_835_ER_162
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Thomas Jacob and Elizabeth Robinson. Discussed topics include displaced people from the Second Sudanese Civil War; clashes between Palestinian refugee camp residents and Lebanese authorities; the history of the Lebanese Civil War; the African National Congress; a general strike in response to the installation of new Nigerian president, Umaru Yar'Adua; the death of Mullah Dadullah; and the rise of religious fundamentalism in Pakistan.
  - June 4, 2007, TW_TAM_835_ER_163
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Hector Javkin and Elizabeth Robinson. Discussed topics include the ongoing conflicts between Lebanese authorities and Palestinians in the Nahr al-Bared refugee camp; the Venezuelan government's refusal to renew RCTV's contract and resulting protests; Venezuelan politics and economy; and the beginning of President Charles Taylor's trial at the Hague.
  - June 18, 2007, TW_TAM_835_ER_164
    The moderator of the episode was Elizabeth Robinson and the guests were Hector Javkin and Katia McClain. Discussed topics include the 33rd G8 Summit meeting; the U.S. wanting to place military bases across Europe; President George W. Bush's positive reception in Albania; the history of the Falklands War and anniversary celebrations; the newly elected Hamas government in Palestine; and the ongoing conflict between Israel and Palestine in Gaza.
  - July 9, 2007, TW_TAM_835_ER_165
    The moderator of the episode was Elizabeth Robinson and the guests were Gerard Pigeon and Cedric Robinson. Discussed topics include growing Islamophobia in the U.K., Nigeria filing criminal charges against Pfizer, Somali refugees being held in Ethiopia, an international conference in Brussels on immigration, assassination attempt against Ivory Coast prime minister Guillaume Soro, the release of Palestinian prisoners to President Mahmoud Abbas, and the planned construction of Israel's West Bank wall.
  - July 16, 2007, TW_TAM_835_ER_166
    The moderator of the episode was Elizabeth Robinson and the guests were Cedric Robinson and H.L.T (HQ) Quan (Asia). Discussed topics include social, economic, and political restructuring occuring in China; attempts to end the violence in Somalia with a reconciliation conference with Somalia's many clans; and the assassination of Sahar Hussein Al Haidari.
  - July 23, 2007, TW_TAM_835_ER_167
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Katia McClain and Elizabeth Robinson. Discussed topics include Bulgarian medical personnel jailed in Libya since 1991; the fate of Kosovo; Jafar Panahi's film Offsite; Iraq War veterans revealing American wartime atrocities; and the Ogaden National Liberation Front in Ethiopia.
  - July 30, 2007, TW_TAM_835_ER_168
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Gerard Pigeon and Elizabeth Robinson. Discussed topics include Robert Gates and Condoleezza Rice's visit to Saudi Arabia; controversy surrounding U.S. aid to Israel; changes in Cuban politics; and the election of Nicolas Sarkozy in France and his visit to Africa.
  - August 6, 2007, TW_TAM_835_ER_169
    The moderator of the episode was Elizabeth Robinson and the guests were Hector Javkin and Cedric Robinson. Discussed topics include the Iraq War, the election of Ellen Johnson Sirleaf as President of Liberia, the hybrid UN-African Union force in Darfur (UNAMID), violence in Somalia, ongoing trials related to crimes from Argentina's "Dirty War," and political instability in Egypt.
  - August 13, 2007, TW_TAM_835_ER_170
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Gerard Pigeon and Huwe Jikata (Africa). Discussed topics include political unrest in Nigeria; the environmental effects of oil extraction and the demands of oil workers in the Niger Delta; the history of colonialism in Africa; and investigations of international business practices in Southeast Asia.
  - August 20, 2007, TW_TAM_835_ER_171
    The moderator of the episode was Hector Javkin and the guests were Katia McClain and Gary Colmenar. Discussed topics include the trial of Bulgarian medical professionals jailed in Libya; U.S. visa requirements to and from EU countries; elections in the Philippines and President Gloria Macapagal Arroyo; Antonio Triana and his senatorial coup; and an earthquake off the coast of Peru.
  - September 10, 2007, TW_TAM_835_ER_172
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Hector Javkin and Elizabeth Robinson. Discussed topics include the death of Rita Solinas; the Iraq War; comparisons between the Iraq War and Vietnam War; the anniversary of an attack against General Augusto Pinochet in Chile in 1973; socialists winning the election in Argentina; undocumented citizens fleeing from Zimbabwe into South Africa; and corruption allegations against Daniel arap Moi and his family in Kenya.
  - September 17, 2007, TW_TAM_835_ER_173
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Katia McClain and Elizabeth Robinson. Discussed topics include discrimination against the Roma community in Bulgaria; the rise of the right-wing in Bulgaria; the Nisour Square massacre and Blackwater Security Consulting scandal; the 25th anniversary of Sabra and Shatila massacre; and undocumented peoples from Zimbabwe relocating to South Africa.
  - September 24, 2007, TW_TAM_835_ER_174
    The moderator for this episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Gary Colmenar and Gerard Pigeon. Topics discussed include the Jena Six; France's new far right laws on immigration; revelations that Guadeloupe and Martinique were poisoned with pesticide sprayed by the French on banana crops; the anniversary of President Ferdinand Marcos signing Proclamation No. 1081 and establishing martial law Philippines; and China sending 315 engineers to Sudan to help build bridges, roads, and explore water sources.
  - October 1, 2007, TW_TAM_835_ER_175
    The moderator of the episode was Elizabeth Robinson and the guests were Thomas Jacob and Katia McClain. Discussed topics include U.S., EU, and Russian negotiations in New York City with the leaders of Kosovo and Serbia to discuss Kosovo's future status; the Bosnian War; cluster bombs and anti-mine treaties; the upcoming Pakistani elections; the insurgency in Khyber Pakhtunkhwa; and the Taliban's control over poppy production in Afghanistan.
  - October 8, 2007, TW_TAM_835_ER_176
    The moderator of the episode was Elizabeth Robinson and the guest was Hector Javkin. Discussed topics include immigration from Zimbabwe to South Africa; Zimbabwean politics and the economy; a Costa Rican referendum on joining the Central America-Dominican Republic Free Trade Agreement (CAFTA) and the effects of CAFTA on Central America; the anniversary of Che Guevara's capture in Bolivia; and Blackwater activities in Iraq.
  - October 15, 2007, TW_TAM_835_ER_177
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Gerard Pigeon and H.L.T (HQ) Quan (Asia). Discussed topics include protests and political arrests in Myanmar and the Saffron Revolution; the alliance between China and Myanmar; President Hu Jintao calling for peace with Taiwan as long as they stop pursuing independence; President Hu Jintao's new economic policies in China; a move towards the removal of Christopher Columbus statues in South America; the anniversary of the Paris massacre of 1961; and the tightening of immigration laws in France.
  - October 22, 2007, TW_TAM_835_ER_178